In this video, I'll be talking about
magnetic
flux and what it is used for.
First of all, magnetic flux is the amount
of
magnetic field passing over a certain
area.
For example, if we took a magnetic field
that
looks like this, it's pointing into the
page,
and let's say we took an area of two by
two,
the magnetic flux would be the numerical
value
of these four units. When you increase the
area,
let's say to three by three now, the
magnetic
flux goes up as well, so it's proportional
to
area. The magnetic flux, phi, is equal to
the
magnetic field, the strength of the
magnetic
field, times the area, times cosine theta.
Now, what does cosine theta mean? Well, if
you
imagine this on a 3D plane, and we have an
axis
for the area over here, you can actually
rotate
this area.
For example, if you rotate it like this,
it
would look something like that now. And
when
you rotate it at an angle of theta, there
are
going to be less x's in the area now.
So as the angle of rotation goes up, the
number
of x's actually decreases.
Until, let's say, it's directly facing
forwards.
So this would be the area, but you can't
see
anything except a line, because it's going
facing
that way. And that's when cosine is 90
degrees,
and that's why cosine 90 is zero, so the
magnetic
flux will be zero, because there will not
be
any axis. So, ultimately, magnetic flux is
a
great way to measure the total amount of
magnetic
field. Calculating essentially the
strength
of the magnetic force through a surface.
And it's really useful for calculating the
strength
for powering devices such as generators,
motors,
and transformers, because you can
calculate
motion when it's converted to electricity,
or
vice versa.